

Charl Roux

Front End Developer

Contact

Address

Pretoria, South Africa 0181

Phone

0829543244

E-mail

charlroux641@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com /in/charl-roux-50b124122/

Technical Profile

- HTML
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Git
- WordPress
- Bootstrap
- jQuery
- Angular
- TypeScript
- GitHub
- Figma

Competencies

Web Developement

Front End Developement

Frontend Developer with proven experience at companies in helping create and maintain a better code base for reusability. Capable of continuous learning while still nurturing junior developers. Experienced Developer with a passion for creating attractive and interactive websites meeting customer needs and exceeding expectations. Well-versed in developing custom WordPress themes. Excels in HTML, CSS, JavaScript and Typescript.

Work History

2021-09 -Current

Front End Engineer

Nclose, Cape Town

- Translated UX and business requirements into elegant code solutions.
- Integrated enhancements into web design to improve user stickiness, smooth functionality, and boost load times.
- Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets.
- Deployed 20+ features to date.

2019-02 -2021-09

Frontend Developer

TouchFoundry, Cape Town

- Combine human expertise and technology to craft products that look, feel, and respond with value
- Role is to write and style front-end components that meet requirements of mocks and full user stories.
- I also monitor and process pull requests for production deployments.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Teamed on user-centric design strategy in translation of UX and business requirements into coded solutions.
- Produced websites compatible with multiple browsers.
- Successfully completed 10 projects.

2018-04 -2019-02

Frontend Developer

BeyondBI, Cape Town

• Beyond BI is made up of dynamic team of

Figma Design

well-experienced business intelligence resources.

- My roles included Web Development, Front-End Development using Angular and Typescript
- This was all done in agile team management space using Jira and Confluence.
- Collaborated with stakeholders during development processes to confirm creative proposals and design best practices.
- Coded using HTML, CSS and JavaScript to develop features for both mobile and desktop platforms.
- Worked on 1 big project with Sanlam.

2017-02 -2018-02

Web Developer

Vivant Studios, Pretoria

- Vivant has developed many successful web design, landing pages, and custom apps for their clients in Pretoria, and greater Gauteng, and also internationally
- Roles included Web Development, CMS
 Development, Front-End Development, and
 Custom Email Signatures.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Provided front-end website development using WordPress, and other editing software.
- Worked on 5 clients as go to person for development and maintenance needs.

2016-08 -2017-02

IT Technician

Evetech, Pretoria

- Evetech sells wide range of high- performance computer components, hardware and gaming systems.
- My roles included building custom PCs to accommodate customer requirements, overclocking gaming PCs, Software installation, Hardware Installation, and Customer support.
- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Configured systems according to prescribed software and hardware frameworks.
- Tested and installed motherboards, processors, and graphics cards on desktops and laptops for

corporate staff.

Education

2016-01 -	Comptia Network+
2016-01	ITTC - Pretoria Treehouse, Non-Degree Program (e.g. Coursera certi cate), Front End Developer, ITTC, Non-Degree Program (e.g. Coursera certi cate)
2014-01 - 2015-01	Comptia A+ ITTC - Pretoria Degree Program
2011-01 - 2015-01	High School Diploma HTS John Vorster - Pretoria

Crossfit

I love being active and pushing my mind and body, being fit helps me maintain a healthy level of energy throughout the day.